<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Shivam Badkas</title>
    <link>https://shivambadkas.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Shivam Badkas</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shivambadkas.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Visual Analysis of Atmospheric CO2 Concentration</title>
      <link>https://shivambadkas.github.io/project/project1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shivambadkas.github.io/project/project1/</guid>
      <description>The University of San Diego keeps detailed records of parts per million of carbon dioxide in the atmosphere at Mauna Loa Observatory in Hawaii, USA. Anthropogenic climate change is the foremost important issue this century and must be met with a global internationally organized pushback. Records from the observatory allow us to graph the effect of international political incidents which may increase or decrease the burning of fossil fuels. The figures are graphed from the year 1970, from when observations began.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Incidence of Age of First Tobacco Use in American Youth</title>
      <link>https://shivambadkas.github.io/project/project2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shivambadkas.github.io/project/project2/</guid>
      <description>The 2014 American National Youth Tobacco Survey provides national data on youth’s (below 18) tobacco related beliefs and behaviours. The survey contains data for state, age, school, sex, rural/urban and ethnicity of secondary school students. The first goal of this analysis is to determine if the state the child lives in is more important than the specific school the child attends. The second goal is to determine whether two non-smoking children are equally as likely to try cigarettes the next month irrespective of age but provided that confounders of sex, rural/urban, and ethnicity and random effects of state and school are the same.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feature Selection for Cancer Diagnosis</title>
      <link>https://shivambadkas.github.io/project/project3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shivambadkas.github.io/project/project3/</guid>
      <description>Link to Project
This was a dataset I found and as I exploring learning machine learning it seemed important to me to pinpoint important features in high dimenensional data. There are a bevy of useful algorithms such as PCA, SelectKbest, and Recursive Random Forests provided by scikit-learn and pandas. I used a cancer diagnosis dataset with approximately 33 features, and the end goal was to find out which features were the most important in predicting the target variable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classification  of Disease</title>
      <link>https://shivambadkas.github.io/project/project5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shivambadkas.github.io/project/project5/</guid>
      <description>Link to Project
This project utilizes many of the standard classification algorithms to predict whether or not a patient has liver disease. The dataset is taken from the UCI repository and is a real world dataset containing 583x11 observations. First, I explore the data, find trends, and just get an overall feel fot the dataset. Next, I use train_test_split to section the data into training and test sets. I use K-NN, a Decision Tree, Logistic Regression, and Random Forest algorithms to create classification models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dimensionality Reduction</title>
      <link>https://shivambadkas.github.io/project/project6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shivambadkas.github.io/project/project6/</guid>
      <description>Link to Project
One major problem of high dimensional data is the difficulty in interpreting and computing data not in three dimensions. The curse of dimensionality refers to the problems that arise with data with a high amount of features, therefore it is wise to reduce dimensions for many reasons including computation, model performance, and interpretability. Principal Components Analysis is a linear unsupervised learning algorithm which essentially transforms the original set of vectors into a new set.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wolf Hall - Hilary Mantel (2009)</title>
      <link>https://shivambadkas.github.io/book-reviews/wolf-hall/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shivambadkas.github.io/book-reviews/wolf-hall/</guid>
      <description>Wolf Hall - Hilary Mantel (2009)
The conflict at the heart of the novel hand is very simple, the king needs a male heir and his wife of 20 years, Katherine, is too old to have more children. His closest and highest ranking advisor, the Cardinal Thomas Wolsey, has fallen out of favour due to his inability to convince the Vatican to grant the divorce so Henry can legally remarry. Enter Thomas Cromwell, the Cardinal’s chief advisor, a pragmatic and practical lawyer born to a blacksmith (important to note his non-noble family) who acts as the Cardinal&amp;rsquo;s ambassador to the king.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shalimar the Clown - Salman Rushdie (2005)</title>
      <link>https://shivambadkas.github.io/book-reviews/shalimar-the-clown/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shivambadkas.github.io/book-reviews/shalimar-the-clown/</guid>
      <description>Shalimar the Clown is British-Indian author Salman Rushdie’s eighth novel, a globe trotting romantic tragedy that reads like a thriller. The title ‘Shalimar’ comes from the famous royal Indian gardens of Kashmir, also the namesake of the titular character. As with many Rushdie stories, the characters embody themes at the heart of the novel, and in this novel their lives are mirrors of the history in which they live in. Rushdie generally incorporates various aspects of South Asian culture and history into his stories, as well as Hindu allegories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quichotte - Salman Rushdie (2019)</title>
      <link>https://shivambadkas.github.io/book-reviews/quichotte/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shivambadkas.github.io/book-reviews/quichotte/</guid>
      <description>Quichotte - Salman Rushdie (2019)
Quichotte quickly become one of my favourite reads, Salman Rushdie’s 2019 novel inspired by Don Quixote is an inspiring and heartwarming novel about family and identity. The novel at its core follows Ismail Smile - a travelling salesman of pharmaceuticals on his quest to win the affections of a television talk show host. His adventures across America present a satire on the sphere of the (first?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ridge and Lasso Regression</title>
      <link>https://shivambadkas.github.io/project/project4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shivambadkas.github.io/project/project4/</guid>
      <description>Link to Project
A common problem that data scientists face is overfitting - their model follows the noise too closely. Regularization is basically a technique that adds a penalty for feature coefficients with large values, L1 and L2 are utilized by lasso and ridge regression respectively. In this project I use a dataset of insurance charges for healthcare expenses of households measure by predictors such as location, number of children, smoking status, and age.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indian Authors and Literature</title>
      <link>https://shivambadkas.github.io/post/political_organization/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 04:36:44 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shivambadkas.github.io/post/political_organization/</guid>
      <description>Since Covid-19 began, I started reading fiction again after negating it for essentially my entire undergraduate career. I started reading more Indian authors and some important works of the Indian Independence Movement which achieved its goal with the newly created Indian Republic in 1947. Reading magazine articles and essays and primary works astounded me as to how really how historically significant the movement was. In particular, it was interesting to see how the various leaders organized their respective communities into unifying faith, class, creed, and gender against the British Empire, perhaps a first in the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://shivambadkas.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2021 21:37:16 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shivambadkas.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Hello and welcome! I am a recent graduate of the University of Toronto where I double majored in Statistics and Global Health. A major theme of my education were the manners and magnitudes in which anthropogenic climate change will affect human populations around the globe. I am interested in using machine learning and data science to highlight the different ways in which climate change will affect life on our planet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Photography</title>
      <link>https://shivambadkas.github.io/photos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2021 21:37:16 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shivambadkas.github.io/photos/</guid>
      <description>I realized that it feels nicer to have photo prints and hold your pictures instead of looking at them on a screen. I decided to get a film camera and then a mirrorless camera shortly after. I love the way film captures light and the process of taking the shot and not knowing how it turned out until the roll is developed.
This is a collection of my photos taken from both my Canon AV-1 film camera and mirrorless Fujifilm X-100T.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migration and Health Research Prospectives</title>
      <link>https://shivambadkas.github.io/post/migration-and-health-research-perspectives/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shivambadkas.github.io/post/migration-and-health-research-perspectives/</guid>
      <description>Groundbreaking and novel research is the pinnacle of scholarship and has been celebrated for millennia. Oftentimes, academics have posed controversial and unconventional solutions to problems and were ridiculed and humiliated only for their discoveries to revolutionize their field of study. The study of human health and migration are both not only controversial and sensitive subjects but are also politically charged. The links between migration and health are overwhelmingly complex and affect each other in various ways, and a new researcher must have ample knowledge of both fields in order to bridge them together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zoonotic Diseases and the Current Pandemic</title>
      <link>https://shivambadkas.github.io/post/zoonotic-diseases-and-the-current-pandemic/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shivambadkas.github.io/post/zoonotic-diseases-and-the-current-pandemic/</guid>
      <description>Reading the Trovao and Nelson papers about the origin and spread of pandemic influenza strains whilst experiencing it firsthand (in the ‘comfort’ of my own home) was quite surreal; it’s rare to read an academic paper that has tangible influence over ones person life. I would like to discuss how developing countries can minimize the probability of incidence of zoonotic diseases. The Trovao paper discussed how modern swine agriculture combined with global trade make the associated influenza virus extremely difficult to deal with.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
