<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Shivam Badkas</title>
    <link>https://shivambadkas.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Shivam Badkas</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shivambadkas.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Migration and Health Research Prospectives</title>
      <link>https://shivambadkas.github.io/post/migration-and-health-research-perspectives/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shivambadkas.github.io/post/migration-and-health-research-perspectives/</guid>
      <description>Migration and Health Research Perspectives Groundbreaking and novel research is the pinnacle of scholarship and has been celebrated for millennia. Oftentimes, academics have posed controversial and unconventional solutions to problems and were ridiculed and humiliated only for their discoveries to revolutionize their field of study. The study of human health and migration are both not only controversial and sensitive subjects but are also politically charged. The links between migration and health are overwhelmingly complex and affect each other in various ways, and a new researcher must have ample knowledge of both fields in order to bridge them together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zoonotic Diseases and the Current Pandemic</title>
      <link>https://shivambadkas.github.io/post/zoonotic-diseases-and-the-current-pandemic/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shivambadkas.github.io/post/zoonotic-diseases-and-the-current-pandemic/</guid>
      <description>Reading the Trovao and Nelson papers about the origin and spread of pandemic influenza strains whilst experiencing it firsthand (in the ‘comfort’ of my own home) was quite surreal; it’s rare to read an academic paper that has tangible influence over ones person life. I would like to discuss how developing countries can minimize the probability of incidence of zoonotic diseases. The Trovao paper discussed how modern swine agriculture combined with global trade make the associated influenza virus extremely difficult to deal with.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
