<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Book-reviews on Shivam Badkas</title>
    <link>https://shivambadkas.github.io/book-reviews/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Book-reviews on Shivam Badkas</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shivambadkas.github.io/book-reviews/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Wolf Hall - Hilary Mantel (2009)</title>
      <link>https://shivambadkas.github.io/book-reviews/wolf-hall/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shivambadkas.github.io/book-reviews/wolf-hall/</guid>
      <description>Wolf Hall - Hilary Mantel (2009)
The conflict at the heart of the novel hand is very simple, the king needed a male heir and his wife of 20 years Katherine was too old to have more children. His closest and highest ranking advisor, the Cardinal Thomas Wolsey fell out of favour due to his inability to procure the divorce from the Pope in the Vatican. Enter Thomas Cromwell, the Cardinal’s chief confidant and advisor, a pragmatic and practical lawyer born to a blacksmith (important to note his non-noble family) who gains Henry’s trust and becomes the de facto chief advisor to the king.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shalimar the Clown - Salman Rushdie (2005)</title>
      <link>https://shivambadkas.github.io/book-reviews/shalimar-the-clown/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shivambadkas.github.io/book-reviews/shalimar-the-clown/</guid>
      <description>Shalimar the Clown is British-Indian author Salman Rushdie’s eighth novel, a globe trotting magical realism tragedy that reads like a thriller. The title ‘Shalimar’ comes from the famous Indian dynasty Mughal gardens of Kashmir, also the name of a character. As with many Rushdie stories, the characters themselves represent themes that Rushdie has given them, and their lives are mirrors of the history in which they live in. Rushdie generally incorporates Hindu allegory into his novels, as well as various aspects of South Asian culture and history.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quichotte - Salman Rushdie (2019)</title>
      <link>https://shivambadkas.github.io/book-reviews/quichotte/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shivambadkas.github.io/book-reviews/quichotte/</guid>
      <description>Quichotte - Salman Rushdie (2019)
Quichotte quickly become one of my favourite reads, Salman Rushdie’s 2019 novel inspired by Don Quixote is an inspiring and heartwarming novel about family and identity. The novel at its core follows Ismail Smile - a travelling salesman of pharmaceuticals on his quest to win the affections of a television talk show host. His adventures across America present a satire on the sphere of the (first?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
